

Salesforce Developer with 7.5 years of experience along with Platform Developer 1 certification. Seeking a role as Salesforce Developer with key skill apex, visual force page, apex trigger, configuration in salesforce.com



Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Noida Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Salesforce Developer, Data Loader, Software Development, Software Design, Data

Migration, Apex, Visualforce, HTML, Javascript, Deployment

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Worked for Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd. with an overall IT Experience of 7.5 Years in Salesforce.

Having a relevant work experience of 6.5 Years in Salesforce Development and 1 Year in salesforce Testing/Admin.

Experience in Administration, Configuration, Customization, Implementation and Support of Salesforce CRM based Application. Worked on Asynchronous Apex - Batch Apex, Future Methods and Scheduled Apex.

Developed 12 Apex Classes, 8 Apex Triggers and 12 Visualforce Pages (Standard and Custom Controllers) based on the business needs.

Experience in realizing the business requirements on Salesforce.com platform by designing the required the entities like Junction Object, Master-Detail and Lookup relationships.

Created 10+ Validation Rules based on the functional requirements.

Proficient in Data Migration from external systems to salesforce using Data Loader.

Work Experience

Capgemini as Salesforce Developer (Consultant) Jul 2014 to Dec 2020

Client: RMIT University. April'18-Present

Location: Bengaluru, KA, India Role: Salesforce.com Consultant

The Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology usually known as RMIT University is a research university established in Melbourne, Australia. There are four application belong to RMIT Project as RM-Relationship Management, ECB-Education Course Builder, RSTP, AMS. RM-Relationship Management will take care by Salesforce.

Responsibilities:

Interacted with various business team members to gather and documented the requirements. Implemented the requirements on Salesforce.com platform and worked closely with SalesForce.com consultants while implementing the solutions for the requirements.

Worked on Batch Apex and Scheduled Apex for various business needs.

Designed, Implemented and deployed the Custom Objects, Page Layouts, Custom Tabs, Apps to suit to the needs of the applications.

Customized application to incorporate the business requirements which involved creating custom Duplicate Rules and Matching Rules for Contacts and Accounts.

Designed, developed and deployed 8 Apex Classes & 4 Apex Triggers and Packages for various functional needs in the applications.

Pages, Workflows & Validation Rules and Custom fields & Objects.

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=2acb15506a737cd16963335b3d278d64090e5858494600470a44435d5...

Created the 20 Workflows and Process Builders for automated field update and alerts.

Enhanced data cleanliness and accuracy by 60% by adding custom Validation Rules, Sharing Settings and Custom Formulas.

Implemented 10+ Custom Reports and deployed them for different business user levels.

Data Migration done from external systems to salesforce using Data Loader.

Involved in framing 20+ Test Classes as part of the Unit Testing phase and the Deployment phase.

Tools / Environment: Salesforce.com platform, Role Hierarchies, Sharing Model, Email Services/Alerts, VisualForce, Apex DataLoader, Workflow & Process Builder, Reports and Custom Objects.

Client: GCI Prepaid April'16-March'18

Location: Bengaluru, KA, India

Role: Salesforce.com Associate Consultant

This application is Telecom based application from Alaska. There are two types of user will be using this application. First user is CSR user who will be using this application on outlets and another one is self-care user who will be using this application by them self. Customer can take network connection by reaching prepaid outlets. Customer's/users have to provide their personal details to get prepaid connection by opening their account on prepaid application. Once users activate their account after that they can operate their account by CSR user or by them self.

Responsibilities:

Connecting daily status call with client.

Used JIRA tool for user stories.

Created Impact analysis document for maintenance ticket.

Used to send Impact analysis document to the client to get approve to start work on it.

Estimate the user story based on complexity.

Deliver requirement based on estimate time.

Proposed Salesforce reporting feature to the client on home page to better visualization.

Used change set for production deployment.

Used SVN for version control system.

Tools / Environment: Salesforce.com, User, JIRA Defect Logging, Smoke Testing, Impact Analysis Document, SVN.

Client: Coke Oct'14-Dec'15

Location: Bengaluru, KA, India

Role: Salesforce.com Associate Consultant

This is the Retail online based application developed using Force.com, Html, Css, Java script. This application included standard object of salesforce Leads, Accounts, Contacts, Cases. In Lead object customer information has to fill as enquiry details. There are 7 outlets like 'Burger King', 'McDonald's' etc. which will be using this application.

Aspire Software Consultancy as Junior Salesforce Developer Jun 2013 to Jun 2014

Aviva Software Pvt Ltd as Software Tester Aug 2011 to Oct 2012

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from University of Pt. Ravi Shankar Shukla University in 2008

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma in Advance Computing-Software Application

Plateform Developer 1 Salesforce

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=2acb15506a737cd16963335b3d278d64090e5858494600470a44435d5...

APEX, Visual Force, HTML and JavaScript
WINDOWS
Postman Rest Client, Force.com
Data Loader, Conga Composer, Workbench

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
marathi				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time